[Music]
[Applause]
here are two different leg workouts I
performed last week and I wanted to walk
you through the rationale and kind of
show off what I have here at GL Fort
Lauderdale so this first exercise um
well I should say one of the workouts
the first workout is more glute dominant
and the second workout is more leg
dominant and just more daunting in
general but all right so workout number
one begins with the body Masters low
back machine now the reason why I chose
this first and hip thrust second is
because I've gotten so strong at hip
thrust they're intimidating right now I
always try to set PRS but I'm just it's
too daunting to go for PRS which I'll
get to in a minute so this body master
low back machine was actually
discontinued in probably the early 2000s
probably over 20 years ago but I used
this machine way back in the day and I
loved it I just recently figured out how
you could load plates at that front
lever position so I did the stack for 30
reps then I loaded up 75 lbs and did it
for 20 reps and then my third set is 100
lb for 15 reps which was a new a new
record but this loading the plates out
this far because torque equals force
time perpendicular distance so even
though it's only you know you know 75
and 100 lb it's so far out it
probably is equal to the stack itself
which is 300 lb so this is a huge this
is really a lot of weight and this this
bent leg hip extension so it's funny it
says body Master is low back machine but
it's not a low back this is bent leg hip
extension you don't feel this in your
low back this is like doing a hip thrust
pulse um but you can see I kind of put
my myself in the Frog position um I feel
it more that way but
it's bent leg hip extension it takes
your quads out of it and you fill it
almost all in the glutes so I
annihilated my glutes before I moved on
to hip thrust which drastically
diminished the weight I could use on hip
thrust so this is six plates per side
585 I've done this for 10 I only got it
for five the next set this is $4.95 I've
done this for 20 reps but I only got it
for
10 and then the third set I got 405 for
12 I've done that for 30 reps
but um it's funny whenever I'm my glutes
look the best is when I'm strongest at
hip thrust um right now I've been kind
of focusing on my squats and Deads just
for the last few weeks and it's really
hard to keep all your strength up on
every
lift that's something that I've noticed
kind of happens when you are your
strongest at in general kind of all the
lifts go up but it is easier to
specialize in one lift compared to
another and right now I'm definitely
focusing on on my squats because I can
squat again that I'll get to that in leg
workout too so now that I did bent leg
hip extension and hip thrust I move on
to the gluteator this is hip extension
and hip abduction at the same
time and it's amazing this really hones
in on the glutes and this is basically
four plates two plates per side I got 30
reps and then the second set I do I add
a 25 on each side so basically you know
two plates and a 25 for 20 reps which
both of these are tied PRS um the thing
about these and hip thrusts you can see
if you have any belly fat it makes it
look so much worse it makes you look
like an out of shape beer
bellied bear bellied lazy
slob but that's cuz you're pushing out
against your stomach but anyway I got 20
reps here this is really hard my my
strongest girls are using like a one a
45 and a
25 and the the beginner females use a 25
on each side um so now after the
gluteator I move on to glute media hip
thrust these are my favorite glute
medius exercise right
now and I got to where I could use 45
lbs for 25 reps and I didn't want to go
for 30 it's just too many
reps so I moved to dumbbells the plates
are nice especially the BC strength
plates because you can hold on to a 45lb
plate by the handle and having handles
on the plates makes this really
convenient but this is a I believe a 60
lb dumbbell and I got it for 20 reps
uh and then I move on to an 80 lb
dumbbell which I got for 15 reps but
this is working people think it's
working the up leg it's working the down
leg the grounded leg you're driving
laterally and if you kind of freeze at
the top you see that right glute
medius well that dumbbell is really far
away from that right glute media so
again going back to torque this is going
to induce a huge torque on that right
glute medius so you you'll fill in the
top leg but the grounded leg is the one
being primarily worked so now here this
is a a PR 80 lb 15 reps this was brutal
and it's
uh you get this right you're moving just
in the frontal plane left to right and
you're stretching the glute on the way
down and then shortening it on the way
out so after these I'm pretty
annihilated um I've hit four straight
glute exercises right the body Master's
low back
machine the hip
thrust the Glu and now the glute me is
hip thrust
um you want to hold on to something
stable here both things I held on to on
these sets were moving around but I tend
to use the squat rack but I thought this
would be better filming it
here um so now I move on I do just a
little bit of hamstrings I did three
sets of three Nordic ham curls and here
I like to flex the hips a little bit
that's why I built this Nordic ham
elevated like this because you can Flex
the hips and go all the way down into
full knee extens ension it works better
when you're slightly flexed at the hips
if you try to be straight up like in
full hip extension you don't get as good
of a set um so I did yeah just a few
sets of three wraps but I find when I do
these on an off day it just my
hamstrings stay stronger so I throw
these in on my glute day it doesn't beat
me up at all and it just helps my my
deadlift strength my keeps my hamstrings
strong so after the Nord I did I think I
did one more exercise or two more I move
on to seated hip adduction now I have
the strongest adductors this is the
stack which is 305 plus an additional
100 so 45 lbs I believe I got 25 reps
which I think tied up
here I think most more of my adductor
growth comes from
squats um squats work the adductor
magnet so well
but I always throw in some seated hip
adduction
because I feel like it works the longest
and the brev well and the
adductors they look really
cool when they're developed so I threw
another 100 lb plate on so this is 55 lb
I think I got eight or 10 reps
um maybe less I can't remember but I was
so fatigued off of the first set Maybe
we only got six but I was so fatigued
now this is like workout number two
which is more brutal I did some warm-up
sets
and hit a low bar 405lb squat now I've
done this for three reps before but this
was cool cuz I haven't done it in a
while you can see I turn my squats into
good mornings I've always done that my
quads have never been strong enough even
though I work them hard my knees just
get sore my quads get sore I can't do as
much volume and then this is a 605 lb
Sumo deadlift I've done this for five
reps I've my my Max deep squat is 455
and my Max Sumo deadlift is
655 but I I think actually 650 I think
but I almost hit a 675 lb deadlift twice
I almost locked it out but the reason
why I'm happy with this is I haven't
been able to hit these numbers I haven't
been able to do squats and Deads lately
that much so this was cool for me it
feels good to be using big weights again
now I move on to high bar chain Squad so
this is 130 lb of chain so this is 225
at the bottom and 355 at the top but it
does allow you to stay a little more
upright um because it's easier at the
bottom and you will feel this annihilate
the quads but interestingly I did a set
of 10 here the last few reps I felt were
like a hip thrust I was feeling my
glutes up top at the lockout and it was
brutal um it felt like I was doing a hip
thrust it was crazy so I love using
chains and bands to overload the lockout
a lot of people like me I fail the squat
at the top I fail the deadlift at the
top I need to be doing um you know
lockout work and then I moved on to
stiff leg deadlifts so keeping the hips
really high taking the quads out of it
and I got 495 for five I think my record
is
six um but this was this felt good I
think I could have gotten six if I
really wanted to but I sometimes I've
I've drained my hamme twice doing stiff
legs so I try to keep a rep in the tank
now I move on to leg extensions and
couple of things about this leg
extension number one you want to do leg
extensions for the rectus femoris in
order to maximize growth of the rec fem
you got to do leg extensions or
squats you got to do a single joint knee
extension movement but I like this knee
extension because it's plate loaded it
it hits the top so strengthen the quads
in a short position all the other
exercise you do for quads strengthen
them in a lengthened position of stretch
this hits them hardest in the squeeze so
that's why I have this kind of all my
other machines you can see are high
quality and then I have this crappy
plate loaded leg extension but I love it
and then I moved on to the lying leg
curl this is 235 lb so almost the whole
stack I got 12 reps tied a PR whenever
my hamstrings are super strong my
deadlift is strong um so doing nordics
and glute ham raises and all three types
of leg curl machines seated lying and
and
kneeling they I don't feel like they're
the best transfer have the best transfer
to deadlift but it's just every time I
my strong as it deathless my hammies are
strong as hell
too all right now I move on to banded
sumo squads I'm trying to strengthen my
Sumo deadlift lockout here and so I'm
trying to hit quads so this is my my top
set I did I have bands on there and I
got 25 reps here but this was brutal um
my quads were screaming so hard here
it's it's it doesn't seem like it' be it
seems like this short range emotion but
I'm telling you I quit doing lockout
work I've been doing partial leg presses
and More band work and really trying to
strengthen my knee extension lockout and
it helps my
deadlift um you know deadlifts you're
not going that deep when you do Sumo
deadlifts most people aren't super
upright like the best deadlifters in the
world most people especially women
you're bent over more if you look at
your Sumo deadlift and how much range of
motion you're using in the knees you'll
see that it's like a partial and you
need that to be strong and then finally
I move on to banded 45° hyp
so I we do round back feet flared to
make it more glute dominant but when I
do these banded I try to keep my feet
straighter and I come up as tall as
possible and the reason why is because
if I was rounded I wouldn't be
stretching that band much if I'm neutral
and come up as high as I can you stretch
the bands so much more so they I got 25
reps with this which tied a
PR and that concludes workout number two
workout number one I did more volume I
did several sets of all the exercise
workout two I only did one hard set of
everything but I like doing that
sometimes thank you for watching I hope
you enjoyed it